Elnaz Doostdar Portfolio

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>elnazd@gmail.com</u>

Senior UX Designer

A seasoned designer with a versatile spectrum of skills tackling highly complex projects with efficiency and impressive results in an enterprise SaaS setting. Fast synthesis of requirements and formulating a design direction that always places the user at the focal point. Develop strong relationships with UX researchers, developers, product managers, stakeholders, and users by tailoring a flexible style to meet success.

Technical Skills

User Research Survey / Interview, Empathy Map, Competitive Analysis, Literature Review, User Flow,

Affinity Diagram, Persona, Journey Map, Usability Testing

Design Hand Sketch, Wireframe, Hifi Mockup, Prototype, Information Architecture, Design

System, Responsive Web, iOS & Android

Development HTML5, CSS3, jQuery / JavaScript, Bootstrap, React

Tools Figma, Miro, Sketch, Adobe Suite (XD / Photoshop / Illustrator), Balsamiq, InVision,

Frontify, Zeplin, Visual Web Optimizer, Keynote

Professional Experience

EQUINIX, Sunnyvale, CA **Senior UX Designer**

Jun 2020 - Present

- Design an interactive self-served centralized network exploration and topology tool empowering network architects to design intelligent network solutions, build, configure, order, monitor, and troubleshoot their entire network
- Redesign Equinix interconnection portal information architecture to reflect relationships amongst networking elements and improve discoverability based on the user's mindset.
- Create an automated online self-service ordering experience for reserving servers that reduces expenses for customers and the business.
- Contribute to the Equinix design system by leading workshops to scale and improve components.

QUEST SOFTWARE, Aliso Viejo, CA Senior UX / UI Designer

Jan 2016 - Feb 2020

Jan 2018 - Feb 2020

- Preserved 15% of PMs' time on executing projects from planning to closure by designing project planning
 and reporting features for an internal enterprise product from conception to implementation, improving
 workflow for several departments.
- Initiated building a scalable responsive/accessible design library and defined maintenance process slashed design deliverables time 50% and enhanced design consistency across platforms and contributed to 2 major acquisitions rebranding process.

- Launched stunning responsive campaigns, landing, and product information web pages worked seamlessly across 6 different languages on the company marketing website.
- Achieved 10% in deflection by redefining and automating user-flow challenges to contact support.

UX / UI Designer Jan 2016 - Jan 2018

- Evaluated and redesigned Quest e-commerce to create visually stimulating UI and delightful user experience; collaborated with users, stakeholders, and developers. Yielded reduction in customer support costs by 20%.
- Led qualitative and quantitative research efforts such as A/B testing using visual web optimizer, validating
 designs and training team members improving conversion rate.
- Pioneered resolving problems by introducing new tools, facilitating hand-off procedures to developers, accelerating work efficiency.

DELL, Aliso Viejo, CA Mar 2014 - Jan 2016

UI Developer

- Launched pixel-perfect responsive web pages using Bootstrap framework amplified traffic and reduced bounce rate on tablet and mobile.
- Delivered a video gallery site using complex Ajax technology, enabling Dell to integrate overall video strategy across platforms improving accessibility.

QUICKSTART INTELLIGENCE, Irvine, CA UI Developer

May 2013 - Mar 2014

- Developed interactive responsive components in collaboration with remote engineers boosting mobile traffic by 50%.
- Analyzed data and conducted qualitative usability tests with users, improving course registration rates by 0.2%

Side Projects

FREELANCE Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

Product Designer

- Designed a COVID-19 protection concept <u>mobile app</u> to help contain the Coronavirus through heatmaps, test symptoms, quarantine instructions, and assigning available healthcare facilities accordingly.
- Designed a healthcare mobile app to support virtual care adopted by <u>Zocdoc</u> application.

Education

- Master of Information Technology, Web Development, Swinburne University of Technology, Melbourne, Australia
- Bachelor of Computer Science, Hardware Engineering, Azad University, Tehran, Iran
- Certificate of User Experience and Customer-Centered Design, California State University Fullerton, CA